<resources>
    <string name="app_name">           Shwedagon</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <!-- for history of shwedagon pagoda -->
    <string name="history">History</string>
    <string name="theGreatShweDagon">"\u0009 Gleaming in gold and decorated with diamonds, the huge Shwedagon Pagoda in Yangon is a spectacular work of Burmese temple architecture and is the holiest Buddhist shrine in Myanmar.
\u0009 The Shwedagon Pagoda is the perfection of Myanmar History and Culture reflecting the Soul of Myanmar People.
\u0009 The Shwedagon Pagoda was type of Paribawga ceti as the staff, bathing-robe, water-filter and eight sacred hair relics of Buddhas were enshrined. It is not only the object of veneration but also the symbol of Myanma National identity and National Prestige.
\u0009 There are four entrances (mouk) to the Pagoda that lead up a flight of steps to the platform (yinpyin) on Singuttara Hill. The eastern and southern approaches have vendors selling books, good luck charms, Buddha images, candles, gold leaf, incense sticks, prayer flags, streamers, miniature umbrellas and flowers.
\u0009 The Shwedagon and surrounding areas are crowded with many people all times of the day; there are about as many devout locals coming to pray and make offerings as there are visiting monks and tourists with cameras.
\u0009 Myanmar's most famous historical, religious and cultural site, Shwedagon Pagoda was built over 2600 years ago. The architectural features of the pagoda complex relate the history of Shwedagon as well as the traditions, faith and culture of the Myanmar people."</string>
    <string name="historyofshwedagonpagoda">"\u0009 The Legend of the Shwedagon began with the two wealthy merchant brothers, Taphusa and Balika, from Pokhravti, Okkalapa province, came to know the news during their Trading Journey in the central India.
\u0009It was on the Full moon Day of Kason, Wednesday at dawn in Maha Sakarit year (Buddhist era) 103 that Gautama Buddha attained Enlightenment at the foot of Maha Bodhi Tree.
\u0009 One of the spirit (nat) informed them about the Enlightenment of Buddha. Then, the two brothers came to Buddha and it was forty-nine days later after attaining Enlightenment of Gautama Buddha. When they found Buddha, they offered him honeyed-cakes and according to their request, Buddha gave them eight of his hair to be enshrined in Burma.
 \u0009 The merchant ship with the gold casket of sacred Hair relics returned to Pokehravti port on 14th waxing moon of Waso, Sunday in the Buddhist era 103.
 \u0009 On the 5th Waxing day of Wakhaung (July), Saturday, King Okkalapa with thousands of military commanders came to the Okkalapa Jetty (the area in which Botahtaung Pagoda was later built) to welcome and worship the Eight Sacred Hair Relics.
 \u0009 With the help of several nats (spirits), the guardian ogre of the hill and the king of this region of, the brothers discovered the hill where relics of previous Buddhas had been enshrined.
 \u0009 A chamber to house the relics was built on the sacred spot and when the hair were taken from their golden casket, amazing things happened:
\u0009 there was a tumult among men and spirits... rays emitted by the Hairs penetrated up to the heavens above and down to hell... the blind beheld objects... the deaf heard sounds...the dumb spoke distinctly... the earth quaked... Mount Meru shook... lightning flashed... gems rained down until they were knee deep... all trees of the Himalaya, though not in season, bore blossoms and fruit. Once the relics were safely placed in the new shrine, a golden slab was laid on the chamber and a golden stupa built over it.
\u0009 Over this was layered a silver stupa, then a tin stupa, a copper stupa, a lead stupa, a marble stupa and an iron-brick stupa. Then set up flying and turning swords that were never stopped to protect the pagoda from intruders.
 \u0009 Later, the legend continues, the Shwedagon stupa fell into ruin until the Indian emperor Asoka, a Buddhist convert, came to Myanmar and searched for it. Finding it only with great difficulty, he then had the jungle cleared and the stupa repaired.
 \u0009 It is easy to see why the Shwedagon Pagoda is such a holy place for believers.Built on the site of the relics of previous Buddhas, containing the relics of the most recent Buddha, the site of miracles and of royal patronage, this is an important stupa indeed.
 \u0009 The treasures of Myanmar cultural heritages at Shwedagon Pagoda make up the highly recoginition of foreigners about the antiques, monuments, belief, tradition, attitude, behavior and life style of Myanmar people."</string>
    <string name="theoriginalshwedagon">"\u0009 The original Shwedagon Pagoda was built in many different processes.
 \u0009 1. A proper site was chosen in the center of the Singuttara Hill.
 \u0009 2. A large pit or a tunnel was dug out
 \u0009 3. Six large stones slabs were set at the bottom of the pit as foundation.
 \u0009 4. A ship of gold was built.
 \u0009 5. An emerald cradle was placed on the ship of gold.
 \u0009 6. Gold figures of the two merchant brothers, Taphussa and Balika, carrying the emerald cradle on their shoulders were made.
 \u0009 7. A Ruby casket was placed inside the emerald cradle.
 \u0009 8. Eight sacred Hairs of Gautama Buddha were put in the Ruby casket.
 \u0009 9. The Ruby casket was again placed in the gold casket.
 \u0009 10. Then, the gold casket with \"a staff of kakusandha Buddha, water dipper of konagamana Buddha, bathing-robe of kassapa\" was placed on the ship of gold.
\u0009 11. The Repository of relics (8 sacred Hairs of living Buddha, Gautama and the possessions of the three proceeding Buddhas) was enshrined.
 \u0009 12. Then, the opening of the pit was blocked with last stone slab of ruby color.
 \u0009 13. After this, a Gold ceti was built on the blocked stone slabs.
 \u0009 14. Then, Seven small ceti(s) of different metal were built enveloping on each other.
 \u0009 15. Finally, the Original Pagoda \"Tigonba ceti\" of a height of 27 feet was built.
 \u0009 16. The original Pagoda was raised from 27 feet to 66 feet and finally it reached almost to present shape and height (326 feet)."</string>
    <string name="thecolonialistday">"\u0009The British colonialists occupied and fortified the Shwedagon Pagoda during and after the second Anglo-Myanmar war.
\u0009During the first Anglo-Myanmar was 1824-26, the three remains of Lt.R.Doran (no.18, Royal Irish Regiment), J.m Taylor (No.9, Madras Light Infantry) and captain C.G Locke (S.S Winchester) were buried in the North-East (Sunday corner) of the Shwedaon Pagoda platform, but were later on 22.1.1929 removed to cantonment war cemetery after a continuous protest of Myanmar People.
\u0009After the British annexation of Myanmar the Western covered-stairway was closed as a fort by the British forces to the public from 1852 until 6-11-1929 when it was reopened for civilian use.
\u0009 Starting from the burning of rubbish dumps left scattering on the festival Grounds clsoe to the western Entrance, the Great Fire of Shwedagon broke out in march 1930 revaging 23 Tazaungs on the pagoda platform.
\u0009 Note: Only on 27-10-1919 the British Government confirmed its order that foot-wear of any kind was not allowed on the Shwedagon Pagoda platform after a strong protest of anti-footwear campaign led by Barrister-at-law, U Thein Maung."</string>
    <string name="raisingtheshwedagonpagoda">"\u0009 1. King Rajadarit's son, King Banya Yankhike (AD 1426 1446 ) raised the height of the Shwedagon Pagoda.
 \u0009 The plinth was enlarged , the hill was leveled.
 \u0009 He had tried to raise the height of the Pagoda up to 302 feet.
 \u0009 2. The King, Banya Kingdaw (AD 14501453) had managed to raise the height of the Pagoda up to 302 feet.
\u0009 3. Shin Sawpu(AD 1453 1460) sister of Banya Yankhike dedicated a vast area of glebe lands.
 \u0009 The Hills and Terraces were repaired.
 \u0009 The great balustrade and encircling walls were built.
 \u0009 The gardens were built on either sides of the four covered stairways.
 \u0009 The whole platform was laid with stones.
 \u0009 Stone lampposts were erected.
 \u0009 The plinth of the Pagoda was renovated with earthen bricks and stone bricks.
 \u0009 The Pagoda was glided from top to bottom with gold leaf equal to her weight.
 \u0009 All the works of merit at the Shwedagon Pagoda was supervised from a town(now known as Myenigon ) she founded in the northwest sides of the Pagoda.
 \u0009 4. King Dhammaceti (Shin Sawbu's soninlaw and successor) carried on her works of merit.
 \u0009 In 1485 ,Inscribed stone pillars relating to the foundation of the Pagoda were installed.
 \u0009 The glebe lands were reduced to proper area .
 \u0009 A bell (Dhammaceti's great bell) weighting about 289 tons of bronze was donated.
 \u0009 5. Banya Yanse (AD 1492 to 1526) , the son of King Dhammaceti offered a new Htitaw.
 \u0009 The plinth was enlarged and built 68 satellite cetis around the plinth.
 \u0009 6. In AD 1542 , King Tabinshwehti wholly gilded the Pagoda.
 \u0009 7. In AD 1564, King Bayintnaung offered a new \"Htitaw\" and reglided it.
 \u0009 8. In AD 1582 ,King Nanda, son of Bayintnaung offered a new Htitaw.
 \u0009 9. In AD 1618, Ingaboke Sayadaw and the people offered a new \"Htitaw\".
 \u0009 10. In AD 1619, the King, Anautphetlun Min offered a new \"Htitaw\".
 \u0009 11. In AD 1652 , the King, Pintale Min repaired the quake stricken Htitaw.
 \u0009 12. In AD 1663, Pyimin repaired the \"Htitaw\" in Innwa.
 \u0009 13. In AD 1679, the Buddhists cooperated to repair quakestricken Pagoda.
 \u0009 14. In AD 1755 and 1757 King Alaungpaya built four big Tazaungs.
 \u0009 15. In AD 1775 Shinbyushin ruin offered a new \"Htitaw\".
\u0009 16. In AD 1776 Singumin donated a Great Bell for his father.
 \u0009 17. In 1841, King Tharawaddy glided from the plinth to the Seinphutaw and a Great Bell was donated.
 \u0009 18. In AD 1852, the first Pagoda Trustees Sitke U Htaw Lay and U Loo in cooperation with the people of lower Myanmar now under the British colonial rule, had to make all around renovation.
 \u0009 19. On November 19th 26th , 1871 King Mindon's new Htitaw was successfully hoisted.
\u0009 20. On 17th March 1889, the pagoda Trustees in cooperation with the people repaired King Mindon's Htitaw after an earthquake.
 \u0009 21. On 26th February 1921, Hgnemana was to repair after 1919 earthquake.
 \u0009 22. In AD 1931 SeinPhutaw and Hgnemana donated by King Mindon had to be repaired after 1930 earthquake.
 \u0009 23. During the period of 1946 to1999 all the damages of the Shwedagon Pagoda had been repaired by the successive governments and people.
 \u0009 24. The State Peace and Development council on 6th April 1999 had done a great meritorious deed of all around renovation for the Shwedagon Pagoda."</string>

    <!--  for arts and archi : _-->
    <string name="arts">Arts and Architecture</string>
    <!--  nine miracles  -->
    <string name="padamyamyatshinpagoda">"\u0009 Padamya Myat Shin Pagoda was erected on the upper terraces(pyitsaya) right up the Eastern Vestibule of Shwedagon Pagoda. The outstanding fact of this Buddha statue is that the wish people pray at this Buddha is fulfilled, therefore, the statue is situated in a place where is difficult to reach. Only men are allowed to go to pray. And men need an admission card to go but difficult to gain it. Women are not allowed to go that cave. To be visible for everyone, that statue is lived on the TV screens located at each side of east, west, south and north of Shwedagon."</string>
    <string name="weitzarzawgyipagoda">"\u0009 This statue is located at Saturday corner of the Shwedagon Pagoda. Zawgyi images can be seen around over there. In old days this statue was planned and erected with the power of alchemy."</string>
    <string name="shinsawpupagoda">"\u0009 The Buddha statue is situated in Rahu corner. Also called as \"four Barr\" and ShinSawPu Buddha statue. At past, there were four sakar (champac) plants around. Nowadays, we can only see one yellow sakar (champac)plant around there."</string>
    <string name="santawtwin">"\u0009 This ceti was erected inside the sacred hair well Tazaung at Northern side of Shwedagon platform. It is situated opposite to the northern vestibule of the Shwedagon ceti. There was a tunnel at the downward of the well to reach the bottom of Shwedagon. But now, this well was closed and built one ceti over it."</string>
    <string name="shinizzagawna">"\u0009 The image is erected inside the Southern vestibule of Naungdawgyi pagoda at Sunday corner and donated by ShinItzaGawna, the holy monk. At the era of Bagan, Monk Shin Izza Gawna of Bagan period was an accomplished alchemist who had made successfully experiment to turn base metals into gold. . He helped the people with his alchemy power by letting the gold and silver rain from the sky. One side of this Buddha image's eye is narrow and the other eye is wide."</string>
    <string name="boboaungcavepagoda">"\u0009 This image of Buddha statue is erected inside the \"BoBoAung Cave Tazaung\" which is situated between Sunday and Friday corner platform. People affirmed that the alchemist BoBoAung erected this Buddha statue. At the back side of the BoBoAung Buddha, there is Dhammaceti King ceti(pagoda)."</string>
    <string name="shinmahteepagoda">"\u0009 The image of Buddha statue is erected in the northern vestibule of Naungdawgyi ceti(pagoda) at Sunday corner of the Shwedagon platform. About a thousand years ago, the monk Shinmahtee who was famous and adorable holy monk during the Bagan era built and donated it."</string>
    <string name="eastlatpalatpagoda">"\u0009 LatPaLat Pagoda statue is located inside the eastern vestibule, also known as the image of the Kakusanda Buddha. Right palm in the Buddha image is up and open whereas right palms in all other Buddha images are down. Therefore, it was named \"LatPaLat Buddha\"."</string>
    <string name="pyadashinpagoda">"\u0009 This Buddha image of bronze is located between the east approach of the Shwedagon and Tuesday corner, (near to Tuesday corner TagonTaing). There is mercury relics enshrined inside the forehead of the Buddha image, therefore, it looks plump. The distinction of the image is very sublime(admiring) and the structure is well proportioned and masterpiece. Every prayer admits that they feel tenderness and gentleness of soul when they pray at the image of Buddha statue."</string>


    <!-- for seasonal Festival Activity -->
    <string name="seasonalfestivals">"\u0009 Tabaung Festival is the significant Festival of Shwedagon Pagoda because it was the full moon day of Tabaung that the King Okkalapa and the two brothers enshrined the sacred hair relics in the Shwedagon.
\u0009 Thingyan is the Myanmar New Year Festival and revelry in water-pouring celebration every places in Myanmar. At Shwedagon, Buddha images and shirnes are ceremonially washed and monks pray and people offered sumptuous meals.
\u0009 In Kasone Festival, hundreds of religious groups and people come to pour water from bowls into the enclosure around the Bawdi(Banyan) trees with ceremonies. It was the Kasone Full Moon Day or Buddha Day. It is the day on which the Prince Siddartha was born, on which he attained Buddhood and on which he passed away.
\u0009 Waso Festival, Waso Full Moon Day which makes the beginning of the Buddhist Lent. Community prayers are held day and night.
\u0009 Thadingyut Festival is said to be as the end of the Buddhist Lent. When Lord Buddha descended from heaven after preaching his reborn mother, from Tawadaintha when Devas line his route and illuminated the way and the people all over the country light candles to welcome back. As years passed by, it became a tradition and a festival. Many people lit candles and electricity from pagoda platform and top.
\u0009 In Tazaungdaing Festival, Mathothingan weaving contest are held in Shwedagon Pagoda. From evening till before midnight, women weavers feverishly vie with each other to be the first to complete weaving yellow robes. The four robes are offered to the four Buddha inside the main vestibules, Gautama, Kakkusanda, Gawnagamana, and Kassapa."</string>
    <string name="seasonal">Seasonal Festivals</string>

    <!-- activity name for famousthingAcitvity -->
    <string name="famousThing">Famous Things</string>
    <!-- for nine miracles -->
    <string name="title_activity_nine_miracles">Nine Miracles</string>


    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
</resources>
